Hello English learners. Welcome back to English
Pod. My name is Marco and I'm Erica and today we're
bringing you another sci-fi lesson for all of
those fans out there of Star Trek and Star Wars.
That's right and today we're going to focus on
some phrases. We're not going to do any vocabulary
today. We're just going to learn some phrases
that you'll find relating to science fiction.
Okay, very good. So why don't
we listen to a dialogue for the
first time and we'll come back
and look at all these phrases.
Captain, we are under attack by
an unidentified ship. Damage report.
We've sustained heavy damages to
the engines. We've lost our work drive.
We'll have to attempt to make contact.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard of the
Starship Enterprise. We don't wish to
engage. What is the nature of this attack?
Captain Core of the ship
photos. Your ship attack
that will search party. No,
you're not doing it right.
card doesn't sound like
that. His voice is deeper.
I don't cut them core of
the ship photos. Your show.
If you can't do an authentic
Klingon voice, I'll have to
find a more serious Star Trek
fan who can actually act, okay?
But I already fought the
Klingon suit and the wig fan.
All right, very good Star Trek fans.
Apparently, they were trying to act
out one of the famous episodes
where the Klingons attack the Enterprise.
My goodness. I don't know a lot about Star Trek, but
I do know a lot about language and we've got some
great stuff here that will help you understand sci-fi
movies and TV shows in English a little bit better.
So why don't we go now to Fluency Builder?
Fluency Builder.
All right, so the first
phrase that we have
today on Fluency
Builder. Unidentified ship.
Unidentified ship.
If we break it down and look
at the first word, unidentified.
You don't know which one it is.
Okay, you don't know the identity.
Yep, and a ship. I guess
that's short for a rocket ship.
Or a spaceship. Okay, so
we're not talking boats here.
All right, we're not talking
about boats. Very good.
Now I'm moving on to our
second phrase. The Enterprise
lost its warp drive.
Warp drive. Warp drive.
So the warp drive of the
Enterprise is actually something like
an engine that allows it to go
faster than the speed of light.
So super fast, super fast.
But why warp? All right, well if
we take a look at the word
warp, that actually means to bend.
Yep, so like when you warp would, it bends.
Exactly, you bend would or you warp metal. And well
that's kind of the theory behind it is that
they're going so fast that they bend or warp time.
Okay, so warp drive, I think a
very sci-fi specific phrase here.
Right. All right, and for
our third phrase today.
Search party. Search party.
A search party. A search party.
Okay, so what is this? Are we
having a party? What's going on?
Well, when somebody gets lost,
you know, maybe in the woods
or something, you send out
a search party to find them.
So a party would be a
group of people. Exactly.
So that also happens in
restaurants, I think, right?
Right, sometimes you might say
how many people in your party?
In your party, very good.
So party group of people.
All right, so in the dialogue we saw
that actually these were not real star Trek
characters, but they were just acting,
but it didn't sound quite right, right?
Yeah, he said that his voice is deeper.
So a deep voice. Deep voice. A deep voice.
All right, we're going to hear an
example of what a deep voice sounds like.
The one constant through all
the years, Ray, has been baseball.
America's ruled by like
an army of steam rules.
Has been erased like a
blackboard rebuilt in a wrist again.
That is a deep voice.
Now, because his voice wasn't deep
enough, he didn't sound authentic.
Authentic. Authentic.
All right, so authentic. Very easy word.
Real. True to life.
Real to life, right? Not fake.
Exactly.
So Marco, is that an authentic Rolex?
No, it's not.
But thank you for noticing.
All right, so authentic.
And our last word for today, a wig.
A wig. A wig.
W-I-G wig. So a wig is pretend hair, right?
Right. Fake hair. So the hair is not
authentic. Very good. All right, so a wig.
All right, we got some great language here.
And why don't we listen to it one more time,
slow down a little bit in the dialogue.
Captain, we're under attack by an
unidentified ship, damage report.
We've sustained heavy damages to
the engines. We've lost our warp drive.
We'll have to attempt
to make contact.
This is Captain Picard
of the Starship Enterprise.
We don't wish to engage.
What is the nature of this attack?
I am Captain Core of the ship Clothos.
Your ship attacked our search party.
No, you're not doing it right. Core doesn't
sound like that. His voice is deeper.
I am Captain Core of the ship Clothos.
Your ship.
No, if you can't do an authentic
Klingon voice, I'll have to
find a more serious Star Trek
fan, who can actually act, okay?
But, but I already bought
the Klingon suit and the wig.
All right, now it's
time for us to take a
look at more phrases
today in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
All right, so we've got some
phrases here that you can
use together with a number
of different words, right?
Exactly. So the first one, we heard
that data said we're under attack.
We're under attack.
Under attack. All right, so if
we're under attack, it means
that we are being attacked.
Attacked. Someone is
shooting guns at you or
trying to hurt you or
something like that.
Okay, so we are under
attack. Very popular phrase
that you would hear in
war movies or something.
Definitely. Now you can change this by
changing the last word. We are under fire.
Under fire, which basically
means the same thing.
Yeah, except when you're
under fire, there are guns involved.
Okay, so they're
shooting at you. Yep.
All right, we're under attack.
We're under fire. Mm-hmm.
All right, moving on to our second phrase.
We've sustained heavy damage.
Sustained, heavy damage.
So when you sustain
something, you receive it
or you undergo this thing.
So usually it's related to injury or to
receiving some type of negative thing.
Okay, so why don't we
listen to some examples
of how we could use
sustain in context?
Example one. John had a car
accident and sustained a fatal injury.
Example two.
The boxer sustained a severe neck
injury in the championship fight.
Example three.
Luckily the worship didn't
sustain any serious damage.
All right, so you see
we typically sustain
something like an injury
or damage that is negative.
Very good. Mm-hmm.
And the last phrase for today.
What is the nature of this attack?
What is the nature of?
Okay, so basically he's just
asking, why are you doing this?
Right, why, what is the reason? Yeah.
What is the purpose? Mm-hmm.
So again, we have some more
examples of how you could
use what is the nature
of in different situations.
Example one.
What is the nature of your
visits to the United States?
Example two.
What is the nature of the
threat against our country?
Example three.
The nature of my visit is personal.
Okay, so a great phrase
you can use not only
when you're talking
sci-fi, but in everyday life.
Exactly. So why don't we listen
now to the dialogue for the
last time and then we'll come
back and talk a little bit more.
Captain, we are under
attack by an unidentified ship.
Damage report.
We've sustained heavy damages to
the engines. We've lost our warp drive.
Well, I'll have to attempt to make contact.
This is Captain Jean-Luc
Picard of the Starship Enterprise.
We don't wish to engage.
What is the nature of this attack?
I have Captain Kor of the ship Kotho's
viewership attack battle search party.
No, you're not doing it right.
Kor doesn't sound like that.
His voice is deeper.
I am Captain Kor of the ship Kotho's.
Your show!
If you can't do an authentically
on voice, I'll have to find
a more serious Star Trek fan
who can actually act, okay?
But I already fought the
Klingon suit and the wig fan.
Well, Marco, I already admitted
that I'm not much of a sci-fi fan.
I don't really know anything
about Star Trek or Star Wars.
Well, it is a very popular show.
I think it started around the 60s or 70s.
Yep, the first version of Star Trek.
And, well, many, many people follow it now.
They dress up. They know the secret
language that is used on the show.
They know the spaceships.
It's a big culture.
That's true. And,
speaking of culture, I think
we've got a Star Trek movie
coming out pretty soon.
So, some of this language can help
you guys understand it a little bit better.
Very good, yeah. So, if you
have any other questions
or comments related to
not only to science fiction,
but anything in general, please
come to the website, englishpods.
com and leave your
questions or comments.
Well, thanks for downloading, you guys.
And, until next time, goodbye!
[Music]